MUHAMMAD HUSAINI

Lamongan, East Java +62 856-4545-7121 husaini.zuhdi20@gmail.com LinkedIn.com/muhammadhusainizuhdi husainizuhdi20.github.io

PROFILE SUMMARY

My name is Muhammad Husaini Zuhdi. I have 2 years of professional work experience in research and developer company. My current position is as an intern student and a member of the IoT and digitalization division at PT Parametric Solusi Integrasi. PT Parametric Integration Solutions Parametric is a company engaged in the field of technical consulting. I have the ability to develop technology to solve problems effectively. My experience has been successful in implementing several IoT projects, software development and application development in collaboration with various stakeholders to solve the problems encountered. I have a great desire to continue learning and succeed in the world of technology, and ready to contribute to the company where I work

SKILLS -

Electrical : Cable Wiring, Microcontroller Arduino Programming : C/C++(Qt), PHP, Dart(Flutter), SQL,

App Dev Programming: Web app, Software Development, Mobile app, Data Analysis and Visualization

Networking : Network Basic, Internet of Things

Cloud Computing : Digital Ocean

EDUCATION-

Undergraduate/ Electrical Automation Engineering

2019 - Now

Sepuluh Nopember Institute of Technology (ITS), Surabaya

WORK EXPERIENCE-

Internship - Research and Development

September, 2021 - Now

PT Parametrik Solusi Integrasi, Bandung

- Engage in engineering product research and development from development to implementation such as IoT, software development and electric
- Teaching electrical basic SMK Bustanul Ulum students majoring in electrical engineering.

Student - Research and Development ITS TEKNO SAINS, Surabaya

September, 2020 - August 2021

- Engage in engineering product research and development from development to implementation such as IoT, software development and electric
- Collaborating with industry, especially manufacturing in order to be able to solve a problem

Student - Research and Development ITS Team Project Laboratory, Surabaya

January, 2019 - September 2020

- Responsible for both learning and research activities in the laboratory
- Collaborating with vocational schools for training on industrial automation
- Engage in engineering product research and development from development to implementation such as IoT, software development and electric
- Teaching electrical basic SMK Bustanul Ulum students majoring in electrical engineering

PROJECT EXPERIENCE -

Internship - Research and Development

PT Parametrik Solusi Integrasi, Bandung

- Design and Implemented Internet of Things on Renewable Energy Microhydro for implemented in Kemuning village, Karanganyar
- Mobile apps development for data acquisition sensor from get API data logger (Raspberry pi) using flutter framework for implemented in Kemuning village, Karanganyar
- Dashboard monitoring development based on website using PHP for IoT in Microhydro Renewable Energy
- Development Smart Farming Greenhouse on Hydroponic Plants in Greenhouse Bandung
- ITS Final Project for Prototyping Industrial Internet of Things (IIoT) in Heavy Equipment and Fabrication in PT Parametrik Solusi Integrasi
- Prototyping IIOT in Heavy Equipment and Fabrication for implemented in PT TAKA Turbomachinery
- Dashboard monitoring development based on website using PHP for IIoT in Heavy Equipment and Fabrication.
- Software development as a gateway for sending data via the MQTT protocol using C++ and Qt Creator framework for implemented in PT Parametrik Solusi Integrasi
- Mobile apps development for QC Control process in electrical panel using flutter framework for implemented in PT EGA Tekelindo Prima
- Application Development Web Based for the Command Center for implemented in Lombok City

Student - Research and Development

ITS TECHNO SAINS, Surabaya

 Research and Development of OEE Systems for Digitalization in Industrial Manufacturing – PT Universal Tekno Reksajaya, Balikpapan

Student - Research and Development

ITS Team Project, Surabaya

- Web Based Dashboard Monitoring Renewable Energy PLTS On Grid
- Protoyping Overall Equipment Effectiveness System
- PLC based automatic galvalum cutting tool
- Trainer Robotic and Electrical Automation for the SMK Students

ORGANIZATION-

Laboratory student coordinator (Cyber Physical Robotic Industrial and Automation Laboratory)

TRAINING & SERTIFICATION -

- Commite for Indonesian Robotic Olimpiade, Robokidz
- Fundamental of Networking, Course.net
- Fundamental of Dart Programming, Edspert.id
- Fundamental of Internet of Things, Edspert.id
- Fundamental of Data Analys, Revou

PROFESSIONAL REFERENCE -

Dipl.- Aris Budiyarto
Director, PT Parametrik Solusi Integrasi
+62 818-714-536